MUHAMMAD TAHA MUKHTAR

tahamukhtar20@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/tahamukhtar20 | github.com/tahamukhtar20 | +923310148548

INTRODUCTION

Highly skilled and motivated programmer with an impressive track record of delivering exceptional results. With a diverse range of projects under my belt, I am well-versed in various programming languages and possess a deep understanding of software development methodologies. I have a lot of experience developing software, have been doing it for about 2 years now and have many different projects related to it, some of those are listed below.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

OneScreen Solutions, Islamabad (Research & Development intern)

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

FIVERR, (Freelance, Level 1 Seller)

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCES, (National University of Sciences and Technology, Islamabad)

NOTABLE PROJECTS

DILJO (Fundraising Web Application)

A Web application made with NEXT.js, Tailwind CSS, Stripe Payment Gateway, Google Maps API, and Pocketbase. Automated the donation system at NUST and designed it as a flexible fundraising platform similar to GoFundMe with an added element of gamification, i.e Achievement System. Backend was made with pocketbase which is implemented in Golang with SQLite.

Cipher (Banking Management System)

A complete banking management solution utilizing a client-server architecture implemented using Winsock2, symmetric encryption etc. Implemented in C++ and its framework (QT Creator). Uses Hashtables, Multithreading for fast request processing, SQLite for data storage and a user friendly Ui.

CyberNerd (Search Engine)

Uses Data Manipulation Techniques and appropriate data structures for efficient Searching. Made in Python using mathematical libraries such as Pandas, NumPy etc. Has a pretty graphical user interface made using Flask Jinja2 Templates

NUST Student Support Web Application

Built a web application using FAST API with SQLite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap. Implemented deep learning models for grade prediction through peer comparison. Uses web scraping by the requests module and beautiful soup.

MAQUETTE

A web application made using NEXT.js with typescript, and Firebase. Made for a french iron curtain store, with custom features asked by the client, this was a freelance project on fiverr.

For a comprehensive overview of my projects, please visit my GitHub.

SKILLS

- Frontend Web Development: HTML, CSS, JS, React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, React Query, Redux, Redux Thunk etc.
- Mobile App Development: React Native, Kotlin, Java
- Backend Development & DB: Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Sessions, JWT, MVC architecture, Prisma, Mongoose, SQL etc
- Data Analytics & Web Scraping: Pandas, Seaborn, Matpltlib, Scikit Learn, Numpy, NLTK, Requests, Beautiful Soup, Selenium.
- Programming Languages: Typescript, Javascript, Java, C++, Python, Golang, Rust
- Miscellaneous: Git/Version Control, CI/CD, Github Actions, Regex, Docker etc.

NOTABLE CERTIFICATIONS/COURSES

- Coursera: React.js, Technical Support Fundamentals.
- **Hackerrank:** Problem Solving (Intermediate), JavaScript (Intermediate), Python, CSS, SQL.
- LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY
 - Urdu (Native, Fluent)
 - English (Second Language, Fluent)

- **DataCamp:** Data Analytics using Pandas, DataViz using Seaborn, Python Fundamentals.
- **Sololearn:** C++ complete course.